{
    "id": "41691e27094048a0838427f8e1eb2739",
    "title": "Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I really .................................... when I was on holiday.",
            "description": "Enjoyed is a transitive verb and requires an object. If there is no object, we use a reflexive pronoun as the object.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "enjoyed",
                "enjoyed me",
                "enjoyed myself"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4917fb6177af457384b134971332248e"
        },
        {
            "question": "He hurt .................................. while playing football.",
            "description": "We use reflexive pronouns when the object refers to the same person as the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "him",
                "himself",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6e04a8a9f26c4dcca5fe34fdb34f6783"
        },
        {
            "question": "They praised .......................................",
            "description": "We use reflexive pronouns when the object refers to the same person as the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "them",
                "themself",
                "themselves"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1d26ea7493c946ac9d3a225d42873cfd"
        },
        {
            "question": "He patted ...................................... on the back.",
            "description": "We use reflexive pronouns when the object refers to the same person as the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "him",
                "himself",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3b94065070c544c9a5b80427b3fd33de"
        },
        {
            "question": "She was beside ......................................... with sorrow.",
            "description": "A reflexive pronoun can be used after a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "her",
                "herself"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b8c46286a9cb490aa8fe3059f7309e28"
        },
        {
            "question": "He did it all by ....................................",
            "description": "We use a reflexive pronoun after a preposition. ",
            "answers": [
                "him",
                "himself",
                "himselves"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d1c5deb4f5c14d9a8225de2b647a9c5c"
        },
        {
            "question": "No one loves me better than ................................. do.",
            "description": "The reflexive pronoun is used only when the subject and the object refer to the same person or thing.",
            "answers": [
                "yourself",
                "you",
                "yourselves"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c444d631bf52456cae74ea41d146d1a8"
        },
        {
            "question": "He only loves ........................................",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "him",
                "himself",
                "himselves"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c8dee31db8ae43bfa0c924f75660d2b7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Rani and ................................. went shopping yesterday.",
            "description": "The reflexive pronoun is not used as the subject of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "me",
                "I",
                "myself"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "cf9865fea5ff422688c5ed574e3e2c15"
        },
        {
            "question": "The first prize was won by John and ................................",
            "description": "The reflexive pronoun is used only when the object refers to the same person as the subject. ",
            "answers": [
                "I",
                "me",
                "myself"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "65ef6065daa642e3adf52141b5f6619e"
        },
        {
            "question": "............................... wrote this essay.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Me",
                "I",
                "Myself"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bb4fd76bd24a4bf6b629136d2127fccb"
        },
        {
            "question": "You have never offered ................................... any help.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "me",
                "I",
                "myself"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "25b8e4a16eaa4c5b9cddd1fb94e96dc0"
        }
    ]
}